ALEX KIM

ALXK.IO | PROVIDENCE, RI | AKIMO6@RISD.EDU | +1 917 891 5667

SUMMARY

A designer + programmer focused on computational design and digital tools. Currently exploring creative coding and generative form with Processing x p5.js. Building experience in generative machine learning through the training and design of neural networks in Mathematica and ml5js.

A former chef of over 13 years, I have trained at numerous Michelin-starred restaurants in New York City, San Francisco, and Kyoto, Japan. As a chef I have been mentioned through various media publications including Bon Appétit, Eater, and Hypebeast US/Japan.

EDUCATION

RHODE ISLAND SCHOOL OF DESIGN, PROVIDENCE, RI SEPTEMBER 2006 - MAY 2008, SEPTEMBER 2022 - MAY 2023 Currently pursuing a BFA in Graphic Design.

POMONA COLLEGE, CLAREMONT, CA SEPTEMBER 2005 - MAY 2006 Liberal Arts Studies

CERTIFICATES & PROFESSIONAL TRAINING

GOOGLE UX DESIGN PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE

AUGUST 2022 - CURRENT (EXPECTED COMPLETION: SUMMER 2023)

UX foundations and experience with wireframes, prototypes, and user research.

UNDERGRADUATE CODING CERTIFICATE, HARVARD EXTENSION SCHOOL

JANUARY 2022 - CURRENT (EXPECTED COMPLETION: SUMMER 2023)

A three course certificate for the foundational understanding of computer science and the art of programming through the use of algorithms, data structures, encapsulation, resource management, and software engineering through Java, R, Python, C, C++, PHP, JavaScript, Swift, and SQL.

MAD ACADEMY, BUSINESS & LEADERSHIP PROGRAM, COPENHAGEN, DENMARK

OCTOBER 2020

Intensive program for rising leaders in the Hospitality and Food Industry at the MAD campus in Copenhagen, Denmark from chef René Redzepi of restaurant NOMA, led by chef Magnus Nilsson of former restaurant Faviken. The program helps professionals to confront the challenges of managing a team and running a business with a focus on group dynamics and team development, conflict resolutions, financial trouble–shooting, and understanding one's own leadership style in tandem with developing both the everyday practices and the long term vision that a thriving business requires. Attendee by invite to the inaugural session from an international pool of applicants.

WORK EXPERIENCE

UNTITLED.HAUS - OWNER

DECEMBER 2020 - CURRENT

Online store for design, gastronomy, and art related media.

SNOW PEAK, INC., PORTLAND, OR - EXECUTIVE CHEF

FEBRUARY 2020 - AUGUST 2021

Opening chef for Japanese brand Snow Peak's flagship restaurant 'takibi' at their U.S. Headquarters.

KIKUNOI HONTEN, KYOTO, JAPAN - STAGIER

SEPTEMBER 2019 - FEBRUARY 2020

Three Michelin Kaiseki Cuisine in Gion-Maruyama. Chef Yoshihiro Murata.

KAPPO SAKAMOTO, KYOTO, JAPAN - COOK

APRIL 2017 - JULY 2019

One Michelin Kappo Cuisine in the Gion District. Chef Ryuta Sakamoto.

RINTARO, SAN FRANCISCO, CA - SOUS CHEF

AUGUST 2015 - MARCH 2017

California-Japanese Cuisine. Chef Sylvan Mishima Brackett.

BENU, SAN FRANCISCO, CA - COMMIS

JULY 2014 - AUGUST 2015

Three Michelin Modern Asian. Chef Corey Lee.

KAJITSU, NEW YORK, NY - LINE COOK

AUGUST 2012 - FEBRUARY 2014

Two Michelin Shojin Ryori, Kaiseki Cuisine. Chef Ryuta Ueshima.

LANTERN, CHAPEL HILL, NORTH CAROLINA - LINE COOK

JULY 2011 - JULY 2012

YAMAZUSHI, DURHAM, NORTH CAROLINA - COOK

MAY 2010 - JUNE 2011

AWARDS & HONORS

WASHOKU WORLD CHALLENGE, 8TH COMPETITION

DECEMBER 2020

Finalist & Winner for an International Japanese Cuisine Competition operated by the Japanese Culinary Academy and sponsored by the Japanese Ministry of Agriculture, Forestry, and Fisheries.